How does AI fit in all of this and how
it does not?
Usually in UX and in UI, AI is
inspiration.
It doesn't mean it validates all of the
things that you have there.
So,
what you can do in UX is to use AI as a
critique master to do critique for flows
and screens. So, you should do the flows
and screens and AI should do the
critique because you don't have a
designer to do a critique for you or a
product manager.
I mean, you might have mentors that can
do it, but to deep dive you can do that
with AI. You can get inspiration for UI
patterns. What I can tell you about UI
patterns because now um
uh why why designers are important.
In my experience working on I don't know
I think I worked on more than 60
products
as
in a role of a developer, designer,
or product manager
and on countless features, I did a lot
of competitive analysis and I looked on
a lot of other solutions. Also in
innovation labs, I've seen
hundreds or even more products or states
of a product. So,
even though I didn't do it
in a school because there's no school
for that, I saw a lot of UI patterns
for specific things. So, now I do know
when to use what or when to suggest what
in a screen.
But, you can use AI to do that and you
can ask about UI patterns.